# **Mason Chinkin**

(707) 695-5647 | Mason.Chinkin@gmail.com | MasonChinkin@github.io | 828 Center Street, Oakland, CA 94607

### **Summary**

My 2.5 years' experience crafting data driven narratives in the US Treasury's International Affairs Office sparked a passion for working with and visualizing data. I have experience with Tableau, Stata, and R, and am learning to visualize with JavaScript. I am a fast learner who approaches challenges with a constructive, professional, and friendly attitude.

## Experience with...

JavaScript (D3.js), Tableau, Stata, R, Bloomberg Machine, SharePoint, Haver Analytics, MS Office Suite

## **Relevant Professional Experience**

Econ. Research Analyst, International Affairs Office, US Dept. of Treasury, Washington, DC...... June 2015-June 2017

- Worked in a high-pressure environment to take complex, data heavy macroeconomic issues and synthesize easy to understand narratives for use by senior Treasury and White House policy makers.
- Volunteered for the IT Committee and fought for the purchase of Tableau; introduced it into office workflow as a tool to visualize geographic trends and allow senior staff to interact with data. Became the office's go-to adviser on the use of innovative and effective data visualizations.
- Worked with internal technology partners to design and deployed a SharePoint website and memo database for the
  International Affairs Office; presented the final product to a town hall of over 200 users including Assistant and Under
  Secretaries.
- Navigated a large, complex bureaucratic organization to clear memos and introduce new technology; the balancing of many (sometimes competing) stakeholders required professionalism and clear communication.

Intern, International Affairs Office, US Dept. of Treasury, Washington, DC.................................January 2015-April 2015

- Used Stata and Excel pivot tables to explore and visualize large data sets drawn from Bloomberg Machines.
- Cleaned messy Bloomberg data using Stata, which developed an appreciation for using best practices when managing large datasets.
- Supported the Chief Economist's Office in FX debt analysis and day-to-day projects.

## **Other Relevant Experience**

## Self-led training in programming and data visualization

- JavaScript (D3.js)- Interactive Data Visualization for the Web, an introduction to designing with D3 by Scott Murray
- R and Tableau- Coursera courses on data visualization

Washington D.C. Chapter Leader, UC Davis Alumni Association .......2014-2017

• Lead a team of board members in organizing events and publishing the quarterly newsletter

#### **Education**

B.A. in International Relations